Guide to the Meyer Lissner Papers, 1903-1923 (inclusive), 1910-1920 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
- AS - AV
  - * Young, C. C. - Berkeley 1910-18, 20 & n.d.Calif. Assb. - speaker v.-p. Mason-McDuffie Co.;? Calif. Progressive State Central Com. Lt. Gov of Calif.
- California Outlook - alphabetical in & out together Pacific Outlook 1911, 1912, 13, 14
  re: articles submitted, finances (bills &/or dues), cartoons
  - ? A. E. Norris, asst. editor Calif. Outlook or sec. Will H. Fischer - managing editor 1912
  - F.C. Thorn - mgr. 1914
  - Meyer Lissner - editor 1914
  - E.C. Reusberger - bus mgr. 1912? Circulation Dept.
  - P.M. Hall - Circulation Dept. 1912
  - Charles D. Willavel - contrib. ed. 1912
  - Selah Chamberlain - trustee 1912
  - W.F. Chandler - trustee 1912
  - H.J. [Aline] - Circulation mgr. 1912
  - Bell - U S Senate
  - Jonathan Bourne, Jr. - U.S. Senate 1912
  - John C. Branner, pres Stanford 1914
  - B. M. Brown - ed. Sunset Journal (S.F.) 1912
  - Paul Scharrenberg - Calif St. Fed. of Labor 1913
  - John S Chambers - Calif. St. Controller
  - Calif. Accountancy Bo - T.E. Atkinson
  - Ellwood Cubberly -
  - Joseph M. Dixon - chrmn. exec. com. Natl Roosevelt Com.
  - Emporia Gazette
  - Lucius M. Fall
  - Vincent Gelcich
  - A.E. Grampner - S.F. City Atty 1912,judge Superior Ct. 1915
  - E.K. Hoak - Sunset Magazine
  - Gilbert H. Grosvenor - Natl Geographie 1912
  - Fremont Older - editor S.F. Balletin
  - J.H. McDowell - see Oliver Typewriter Agency, mgr.
  - Outlook Co. - N.Y. - Frank C. Hoyt, treas.
  - Pacific Electric Ry Co. - Geo. L. Bugbee, landagt, H.A. Culloden, audits D.W. Pontius, traffic mgr.
  - Panama Canal, Washington Office - 1914A.L. Flint, asst. to Charge of Aff., (1)
  - [F.C.] Boggs- Maj. Corps of Engrs. U.S.A., Clif. of Off.), (1)
  - Panama - Pacific Internatl Expos. Co. - Louis Levy see Press Publicity Com., clif. Dept. City Press & Info.
    Hamilton M. Wright, ed.
  - Perkins, Geo. W. see also Progressive Natl Com. or HQ
  - Republican Organizations - incl. committeeman delegations (State, L.A. Co., Sta. Clara Co.)
  - Friend W. Richardson - Calif St. Printer 1912
  - Leo S. Robinson - Panama - Pacific Internat'l Expos Cmm.? State Controller
  - Roosevelt Progressive Repub. Lg. of Calif Philip Bancroft, sec.; J.W.Stetson, pres.
  - San Bernardene News - Free Press - W.S. Ingram, mg. ed.
  - S.F. Chamber of Commerce. L.M. King, exec. sec.
  - Sunset Magazine - E.K. Hoak, mgr. S.W. Dept. (L.A.)
  - F.C. Thorn - mgr. 1911Calif. Outlook
  - Lucien Augustus Wait - prof. emeritus Cornell U.
  - A.J. Wallace - 1912 (Nov.)Lt. Gov. Calif.
  - Allison Ware - pres. Calif. St. Normal School, Chico
  - E.O. Weed - chf. dep. assessor L.A. Co.
  - Harris Weinstock - trustee Calif. Outlook
  - E.C. Reus berger - mgr. Calif. Outlook
  - Mary M. Willard = Mrs. C.D.
  - Johnson for Pres. 1920 -corresp., lists, campaign flyers etc.
    clippings - alphabetical - some strange subject headings interfiled = existing order.
  - New Order:
    - Correspondence In (L.A. Exec. Com.) and Out.
      filed together alphabetically by last name of person/or title of organization
  - Calif. State Colored Republican League (1) L.A. - pres. Eldridge, F.W. - mg editor of L.A. Examiner Mrs. Harriet Odgers French see also Harriet Odgers.
  - spec. folders: H.L. Carnahan, George I. Cochran, Hoover Campaign Corresp., Chas. K. McClatchy, Newspaper Advertising, New York Headquarters (H day), C.H. Rowell, San Diego Club (Glenn A. Tucher, sec.), San Francisco Headquarters
  - Hugh E. Macbeth - nego lawyer L.A., member Republican State Central Com.
  - L.H. Leve - Stanford Johnson Republican Club.
  - Johnson for Pres. San Francisco HQ - J.A. Johnstone?; Arthur MacLennan, publicity; H.L. Carnahan, western mgr. campaign; com.
  - [William R.] Hearst?, (1 postcard)
  - Fred E. Lindley
  - Newspaper Advertising - newspapers under name of town, magazines by title
    - Anaheim Daily Herald - s. E.J. Horsley, ed. & mgr.
    - Anaheim (Cal.) Gazette - s. Henry Kuchel, ed. & prop.
    - Artesia News - s. W.E.P. [W.E. Perry] ed. & mgr.
    - Azusa, The Pomotropic - s. R.B. Carrier, ed. & publr.
    - Bakersfield Californian - s. Edward Benson?
    - Bakersfield Morning Echo
    - Beaumont Leader - s. U.S. Lemon
    - Brea Progress - s. W.C. Adkins
    - Calexice Chronicle - s. She. Stock berger, ad mgr.
    - Claremont Courier - s. W. D. Bell, prop.
    - Colton Daily Courier - s. H.D. Dreisbach, ed. & mgr.
    - Corona Courier - s. Charles F. Hildreth
    - Corona Independent - s. Geo[rge] M. Blair, prop.
    - Eagles Aerie - L.A. s. Antonio Apache
    - El Centre, Imperial Valley Press - s. Merrill D. Davis, prop.
    - Elsinor, Lake Elsinore Valley Press - s. W. J. Sergel, mgr. & ed.
    - Fillmore Herald - s. W.E. Wagener
    - Fresno Herald - s. J. Ross William, bas. mgr.
    - Fresne Republican Publishing Co. - s. I.H. Bowell
    - Garder, Greve News - s. Vernon King, publr.
    - Glendale Press - s. H. Foy
    - India Date Palm - s. Harry B. R[eeds?]
    - La Verne Leader - s. Ulmah Knoch, ed. & publr.
    - Long Beach Daily Telegram - s. J. J. Perry, mgr, R.M. Diekinson, adv.
    - Long Beach Press - s. Frank F. Merriam, adv. mgr.
    - L.A., California Voice - s. Wiley J. Phillips
    - L.A., The Citizens Advocate - s. Charles Alexander, ed. & publr.
    - L.A., Commercial Bulletin - s. Lloyd L. Stagger, ed. & mgr.
    - L.A., The Sportsman - s. Antonio Apache
    - Monrovia Messenger - s. C.O. Broxon
    - Arcadia Journal - s. C.O. Broxon
    - Montebello News - s. has C.E. Stivers, publr.
    - Orange Star - s. W.L. Taylor, ed.
    - Oxnard Courier - s. J.J. Krouser, ed. & publr.
    - Palmdale Post - s. Archie J. Hicks, publr.
    - Pasadera Star-News - s. Chas. H. Prisk, mgr. & ed.
    - Perris Progress - s. M.C. Hendricks
    - Pomona Bulletin - s. E.E. King, mgr.
    - Pomena Progress - s. W.E. Stevens, pres.
    - Rialto Record - s. V.G. Hosfelt, ed.
    - Riverside Daily Press - s. E.P. Clarke
    - Sacramento Bee - s. W.H. James, asst. to publr.
    - San Bernardino Index - s. W.A. Yarwood, ad. mgr.
    - San Bernardino Sun - s. A.S. Webster, bus. mgr.
    - San Diego Labor Leader - s. Earl L. Chappell, ed. & mgr.
    - San Diego Sun - s. W.S. Dayton, bus. mgr.
    - San Dimas Press - s. C.L. Compton, ed. & publr.
    - San Francisce Call - s. J.L. Adler, bus. mgr.
    - S.F. Chronicle - st. W.H.B. Fowler, bus mgr.
    - S.F. Examiner - s. C.H. House, asst and mgr.
    - San Gabriel Sun - s. Will G. Gilstrap, ed. & owner
    - Santa Ana Bulletin - s. J.F. Adams
    - Santa Ana Daily Register - s. J.P. Baumgartner, ed. & mgr.
    - Santa Barbara Morning Press - s. W.C. Getty, mg. ed.
    - Sawtelle Tribune - s. Art Yeager, publr.
    - Stockton Record - s. H.J.F. Barkalay?, bus mgr.
    - Van Nays News Publishing Co. - s Frank M. Keffer, ed. & mgr.
    - Ventura Daily Post - s. Alfred H. Davis, publr.
    - Ventura Free Press - s. D.J. Reese, publr.
    - Visalia Daily Times - s. M.M. Maddox
    - Watts Advertiser - s. A.D. Lefavor, mg. ed.
    - Whittier News - s. B.L. Donag ?
    - Zelzah ? s. H.E. Whitaker
NOTE!!
Use of index card files:
The Lissner correspondence is filed in manila folders according to the name appearing first on the card, unless otherwise stated. The cards are filed chronologically. - cards row in boxes 60-68 m chronological order.
Use of Lissner correspondence files:
Letters are filed chronologically under each name in the respective files. In using the Lissner files of letters for the period 1907-1909, it must be noted that carbon copies of letters included were signed by Charles W. Bell, Sidney A. Butler, William Justus Rice, Frank G. Henderson, members of the Lissner office staff, as well as Meyer Lissner. Care must be exercised to detect this as no certain identification mark is used. The following information may be of some help.
Sidney A. Butler was chairman of the Los Angeles County Central Committee of the Lincoln-Roosevelt Republican League
Frank G. Henderson was secretary of this Co. Central Committee of the League
Meyer Lissner was chairman of Executive Committee
Justus W. Rice was secretary of this Executive Committee
Charles W. Bell was assistant secretary of the state organization and is referred to in one letter by Lissner as secretary for Southern California
Meyer Lissner is mentioned by Dickson and Rowell as having been appointed chairman for Southern California
signed: Alice Rose
Correspondents by Year
- 1904 - 1909
  - Anderson, George Baker - 1909 -Secretary People's Legislative Bureau, Sacramento
  - Avery, Russ - L. A. attorney
  - Bancroft, Philip
  - Bard, U.S. Senator Thomas R. - Hueneme, Ventura County.
  - Bartlett, Rev. Dana - Bethlehem Institute, Los Angeles
  - Beatty, John A., Jr. - Santa Ana
  - Bell, State Senator Charles W. - Pasadena
  - Belshaw, State Senator C. M. - Antioch
  - Booth, H. C. - Santa Barbara city attorney; Southern Pacific atty.
  - Brundige, H. W. - editor, L. A. Express
  - Butler, Sidney A. - L-R campaign manager, Los Angeles
  - Coggswell, Assemblyman Prescott F. - 68th District
  - Crow, Judge S. E. - Santa Barbara
  - Davis, W. R. - former mayor, Oakland
  - Devlin, Frank R. - attorney Vallejo; President (1908)Lincoln Roosevelt League of Republican Clubs of California
  - Dickson, E. A. - associate editor L. A. Express, 1907.
  - Drew, A. M. - Fresno
  - Earl, E. T. - Los Angeles publisher; financial support
  - Eshleman, J. M. - attorney from Imperial County
  - Estudillo, Miguel - Riverside
  - Fels, Joseph - soap manufacturer
  - Fleming, A. P. - old time Los Angeles Republican
  - Flint, State Senator Tom - 1907 -Los Angeles
  - Fredericks, J. D. - District Attorney, Los Angeles, 1908
  - Harper, A. C. - Mayor, Los Angeles, 1968
  - Hayes, E. A. - C ongressman from San Jose
  - Haynes, Dr. John R.
  - Heard, Dwight B. - Arizona Progressive
  - Henderson, Frank - 1908Secretary Lincoln Roosevelt League of Los Angeles
  - Heney, Francis J. - San Francisco attorney
  - Hewitt, Leslie R. - Los Angeles city attorney, 1907
  - Houser, Fred W. - Assemblyman
  - Hunsaker, W. J. - L. A. attorney; defended Older in Libel suit.
  - Jacobs, Isidor - California Canneries, S. F.; Good Gov't. Organization
  - Johnson, Hiram - Governor of California
  - Jones, Prof. Wm. Carey - Dept. of Jurisprudence, Univ. of California
  - Kent, U. S. Rep. William - Marin County
  - La Follette, Senator Robert M.
  - Lee, Bradner - 1908 Chairman Republican County Central Committee, L. A.
  - Leeds, W. R. - Los Angeles attorney; assemblyman 1907
  - Long, Percy - San Francisco District Attorney, 1908
  - Luce, Edgar A. - San Diego
  - McLachlan, U. S. Rep. James
  - Newberry, Perry - San Francisco Republican League
  - Nye, A. B. - State controller; former sec. to Governor Pardee
  - Older, Fremont
  - Pardee, George - former Governor of California
  - Pridham, R. W. - L. A. County Supervisor
  - Roberts, E. D. - President San Bernardino National Bank
  - Roche, Theodore - San Francisco attorney
  - Roseberry, L. H. - Atty. Santa Barbara
  - Rowell, Chester
  - Ryan, Daniel A. - candidate for mayor, San Francisco
  - Sloane, Judge W. A. - San Diego
  - Stimson, Marshall - Los Angeles
  - Uhl, Adolph - San Francisco
  - Vorys, Al - Taft representative in Ohio, 1908
  - Wallace, A. J. - Lt. Governor
  - Weinstock, Harris
  - Willard, C. D. - sec. L. A. Municipal League
  - Williams, W. R. - State Treasurer
  - Works, Judge John D.
  - York, Judge Waldo M.
- 1912
  - Bancroft, Philip - Secretary, San Francisco County Central Com.
  - Bartlett, Dr. Dana - Bethelehem Institute, Los Angeles
  - Dickson, E. A. - Secretary, U. S. Senator John D. Works
  - Dixon, U. S. Senator Joseph M. - Chairman National Progressive Com.
  - Earl, E. T. - Los Angeles Publisher -- Tribune, Express
  - Edgerton, Edwin O. - Member, California Railroad Commission
  - Fels, Joseph - soap manufacturer; single-tax advocate
  - Hamilton, John J. - member Los Angeles Board of Freeholders
  - Haynes, Dr. John R. active in L. A. Good Government Organization
  - Heney, Francis J. - San Francisco attorney
  - Hewitt, Leslie R. - Los Angeles attorney
  - Johnson, Hiram - Governor of California
  - Jordan, Frank C. - Secretary of State
  - Kent, U. S. Rep. William - Marin County
  - La Follette, Senator Robert M. - Wisconsin
  - Luce, Edgar A. - San Diego attorney
  - McCabe, Alexander - secretary to Governor Johnson
  - Madsen, Martin C.-- executive secretary to Governor Johnson
  - McCormick, Medill - National Roosevelt Committee, 1912
  - Mott, Frank - Mayor of Oakland
  - Nelles, Fred C. - Superintendent Whittier State School
  - Neylan, John Francis - Member, State Board of Control
  - Older, Fremont - San Francisco Bulletin
  - Pardee, George C. - former Governor
  - Perkins, George W. - Progressive National Committee
  - Pillsbury, A. J.
  - Pridham, R. W. - Los Angeles County Supervisor
  - Richardson, Friend - State Printer
  - Roberts, E. D. - State Treasurer
  - Robinson, Leo - Secretary, Finance Committee, Roosevelt Progressive Republican League of California
  - Rowell, Chester - Fresno Republican
  - Ryan, Daniel A. - San Francisco
  - U'Ren, W. T. - Direct Legislation League of California
  - Walcott, E. A. - Secretary, Commonwealth Club
  - Wallace, A. J. - Lieutenant Governor
  - Willard, C. D. - Secretary, Municipal League of Los Angeles
  - Woodruff, Clinton Roters - Secretary, National Municipal League
  - Young, Assemblyman C. C. - Berkeley
- 1913
  - Bartlett, Dr. Dana
  - Bell, U. S. Rep. Charles W. - 1913,Los Angeles
  - Boynton, A. E.
  - Brundige, H. W.
  - Burke, Dr. William P. - Redlands
  - Camp, E. W.
  - Carr, State Senator William J.
  - Churchill, Winston
  - Chenoweth, Lawrence E. - Bakersfield
  - Clark, Assemblyman Willaim C.
  - Cochems, E. T. - Progressive National Committee
  - de Ligne, A. A. - State Superintendent of Banks
  - Detrick, Charles R. - Railroad Commission
  - Dickson, E. A.
  - Dixon, Joseph M.
  - Edson, Katherine and Charles Farwell
  - Earl, E. T.
  - Fels, Joseph
  - Fernald, Reginald - Santa Barbara
  - Fischer, Will - 1913,Managing Editor, California Outlook
  - Gates, Carroll W. - Los Angeles
  - Gates, Assemblyman Egbert J.
  - Gates, Lee C.
  - Hewitt, Leslie R.
  - Heney, Francis J.
  - Jones, Professor Willaim Carey
  - Kellor, Francis A. - Chief, Progressive Service, Prog. Nat'l. Com.
  - Kent, Senator William
  - Letts, Arthur - Attorney, Los Angeles
  - Lind, H. B. - Progressive State Central Committee, Nevada
  - McCormick, Medill - Progressive National Committeeman
  - Morrison, Willis I. - Attorney, Los Angeles
  - Neylan, John F. - State Board of Control.
  - Pillsbury, A. J. - Industrial Accident Board
  - Richardson, Friend
  - Roosevelt, Theodore
  - Rowell, Chester
  - Stephens, Congressman William D.
  - Stetson, John W. - Pres. Roosevelt Prog. Repub. League of Calif.
  - Stimson, Marshall
  - Stone, George W. - Mayor, Santa Cruz
  - Taylor, B. Grant - Clerk, Supreme Court of California
  - White, William Allen
  - Wiggins, Frank - Secretary, Los Angeles Chanber of Commerce
  - Will, Arthur P. - Legislative Counsel
  - Williams, Edgar - President State Civil Service Commission
  - Williams, Thomas S. - Member State Harbor Commission
  - Woodley, Assemblyman F. E. - Los Angeles
  - Young, C. C. - Speaker of Assembly
- 1915 - 1916
  - Arlett, Arthur - San Francisco; member Panama Pacific International Exposition Commission
  - Baer, John Willis - President, Occidental College
  - Baumgartner, J.P. - Santa Ana publisher; member Conservation Commission
  - Benedict, Stanley - State Senator
  - Blight, Reynold E. - accountant, Los Angeles
  - Bonnheim, A. - Sacramento banker; member Industrial Welfare Commission
  - Bulla, Robert N. - Los Angeles
  - Burnham, George - Philaldelphia; Treasurer National Municipal League
  - Butler, Edwin M. - State Senator
  - Carnahan, H.L. - Commissioner of Corporations
  - Carr, William J. - State Senator
  - Chambers, John S. - State Controller
  - Chandler, A.E. - Member, State Water Commission
  - Cook, A.J. - Commissioner of Hotriculture
  - Devlin, Frank R. - State Railroad Commission
  - Dohrmann, A.B.C. - San Francisco; member Industrial Welfare Commission
  - Edgerton, Edwin O. - State Railroad Commission
  - Edson, Mrs. Katharine P. - Member, Industrial Welfare Commission
  - Eshleman, John M. - Lieutenant Governor
  - French, Will J. - Member Industrial Accident Commission
  - Gordon, Alexander- Member, State Railroad Commission
  - Havenner, Franck R. - San Francisco Bulletin
  - Hichborn, Franklin - Santa Clara
  - Hinshaw, W.E. - Supervisor, Los Angeles County
  - Howard, Ray - attorney, Los Angeles
  - Ickes, Harold - attorney, Chicago
  - Jess, Stoddard - banker, Los Angeles
  - Johnson, Hiram - Governor
  - Johnson, William Templeton - architect, San Diego
  - Johnstone, W.A. - San Dimas; member State Water Commission
  - Jordan, Frank - Secretary of State
  - Lane, Franklin - Secretary of the Interior
  - Lathrop, John E. - American City Bureau, New York City
  - Long, Percy - City Attorney San Francisco
  - Loveland, H.D. - State Railroad Commission
  - McCabe, Alexander - Private Secretary to Governor Johnson
  - McClure, W.F. - State Engineer
  - Madsen, Martin - Executive Secretary to the Governor
  - Martin, Irving - Member, State Water Commission
  - Murasky, Frank J. - Chairman, Industrial Welfare Commission
  - Murdock, Victor - Chairman Progressive National Committee
  - Neylan, John Francis - State Board of Control
  - Phelan, Hames D. - United States Senator from California
  - Pillsbury, A.J. - Chairman, Industrial Accident Commission
  - Rowell, Chester
  - Sinsheimer, Paul - Bond Expert, Railroad Commission
  - Sullivan, Matthew I. - Pres. P.P.I.E. Commission
  - Swing, Phil D. - attorney, El Centro
  - Thelen, Max - President Railroad Commission
  - Thompson, Newton W. - State Senator
  - U'Ren, Milton - Secretary, Direct Legislation League of California
  - Webb, U.S. - State Attorney General
  - Weinstock, Harris - Member, Industrial Accident Commission
  - White, William Allen - Kansas editor
  - Will, Arthur P. Chief, Legislative Counsel Bureau
  - Williams, Edgar - President, State Civil Service Commission
  - Williams, W.R. - Supreintendent of Banks
  - Woodruff, Clinton Rogers
  - Woolwine, Thomas Lee - Los Angeles District Attorney
  - Works, John D. - United States Senator from California
  - Young, C.C
- 1917 - 1921
  - A - I
    - Arndt, Stanley - Stockton attorney
    - Benjamin, Raymond - 1920,Chairman Republican State Central Com.
    - Beveridge, Albert
    - Breed, Arthur H. - State Senator from Piedmont
    - Bradley, Christopher M. - attorney for Industrial Accident Commission
    - Camp, E.W. - railroad attorney
    - Carnahan, H.L. - of Riverside; Commissioner of Corporations
    - Chambers, John S. - State Controller
    - Devlin, Frank
    - Dickson, E.A.
    - Edson, Mrs. Katherine Phillips - Executive Commissioner, Industrial Accident Commission; voluminous correspondence
    - Fellows, C.W. - Manager, 1919,State Compensation Insurance Fund
    - French, Will J. - Industrial Accident Commission
    - Gibson, Hugh - United States Diplomatic Service
    - Graupner, A.E. -Counsel, Industrial Accident Commission
    - Haynes, Dr. John Randolph
    - Hays, Will - Chairman, Republican National Committee; large file
    - Herriott, Paul
    - Ickes, Harold
    - Johnson, Hiram - United States Senator from California
  - J - Z
    - Johnson, Hiram - United States Senator from California
    - Johnson, Hiram, Jr. - attorney
    - Johnston, W.A.
    - Krehbiel, Edward - Professor of History, Stanford University
    - Lasker, Albert - Chairman, United States Shipping Board
    - Luce, Edgar A. - attorney, San Diego
    - Lyons, D.B. - Registrar of Voters, Los Angeles
    - McCabe, Alexander
    - McClatchy, Charles K. - Publisher, Sacramento Bee
    - Madsen, Martin
    - Martin, Irving - Railroad Commission
    - Mueller, Oscar C. - President, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce
    - Myers, Judge Louis W. - Los Angeles
    - Naftzger, A.F. - Industrial Accident Commission
    - Nelles, Fred C.
    - Neumiller, Charles L. - Stockton
    - Neylan, John Francis - 1913-1920files in this drawer
    - Older, Fremont -San Francisco Bulletin
    - Olney, Warren Jr. - California Supreme Court
    - Ozborne, H.Z. - United States Representative
    - Perkins, George W. - Chairman Progressive National Committee
    - Phelan, James - United States Senator to 1917
    - Pillsbury, A.J.
    - Pope, Arthur Upham - Philosophy Professor, Univ. of California
    - Reese, D.J. - State Civil Service Commission, 1917
    - Rowell, Chester - largest single file
    - Russell, Charles Edward - Washington, D.C.
    - Seavey, Claude S. - Member, 1920,State Board of Control
    - Shortridge, Samuel M. - U.S. Senator, 1921-1927
    - Sloane, W.A. - Justice, Supreme Court of California
    - Stephens, William D. - Governor of California
    - Thelen, Max - Railroad Commission
    - Weinstock, Harris
    - White, William Allen
    - Young, C.C.